嘿，把蜡烛放在蛋糕上
SINGER:  Hey, put the candles on the cake
要庆祝吗?
Gonna celebrate
-我们应该谈谈所有的女人吗?
- Should we talk about all the women?
[欢呼和掌声]
[cheers and applause]
哦，我在这部分的表现很糟糕，
Oh, I come off bad in this part of the story,
但这是事实。
but it's the truth.
我就随它去吧。
I'm just gonna go with it.
我是一头猪。
I was a pig.
但是库斯已经走了;我不知道该怎么处理这些破事。
But Cus was gone; I didn't know how to deal with all that shit.
(笑声)
[laughter]
别这样，迈克。
INTERVIEWER: Come on, Mike.
你是说没有一百万个女孩
You mean there aren't a million girls
以世界重量级拳王的名字命名?
after the heavyweight champ of the world?
-不，他们不要我。
- Nah, man, they don't want me.
他们只想要现金。
They just want the cash.
有几百万美元可以花。
Got millions of dollars to spend.
爱一个那样的人很容易。
It's easy to love someone like that.
我知道我长什么样。
You know, I know what I look like.
我每天都在镜子里看到自己。
20.
I see myself in the mirror every day.
没有，但是，我只是希望
Nah, but, you know, I just wish
我可以找到一个在我破产时认识我的女孩
I could find a girl who knew me when I was broke
还以为我是个好人
and just thought I was a nice guy.
我可能背叛过每一个和我在一起的女人。
I probably cheated on every woman I ever been with.
可能永远不会尊重他们
Probably never respect them
因为我从来没有真正尊重过自己
'cause I never really respect myself.
我想，但是……
I want to, but...
我觉得我从没爱过任何一个和我在一起的女人。
I don't think I ever loved any woman I've ever been with.
这很疯狂，对吧?
It's crazy, right?
永远不要爱他们。
30.
Never love 'em.
但是我想。
But I want to.
(性感的音乐)
[sensual music]
歌手:
来牵我的手吧
SINGER:
Come take my hand
(脚步攻)
[footsteps tapping]
相信我
Trust me
全心全意地
With all your heart
-好多了。
- All better.
歌手:
我的每一个字
SINGER:
Every word that I
我说的每一个字
Every word I say
——(呻吟)
- [moaning]
[电视上播放的充满活力的音乐]
[energetic music playing over TV]
堂。科尼利斯:你有一些动作。
DON CORNELIUS: You got some moves.
罗宾·吉文斯:谢谢。
ROBIN GIVENS: Thank you.
唐:罗宾，你15岁高中毕业，
DON: Robin, you graduated high school at 15,
19岁上萨拉劳伦斯学院。
Sarah Lawrence College at 19.
然后你拒绝了哈佛医学院
Then you turned down Harvard Medical School
主演热播剧
to star on a hit series.
这样你就是班长了吗?
Does that make you head of the class?
-唐，
- Well, Don,
有人说我是。
some say I am.
唐:如果你想要更多的罗宾·吉文斯……
DON: If you want more Robin Givens...
-我要娶那个女人。
- I'm gonna marry that woman.
-去你妈的。
- Fuck you.
观众:是的!观众:哇!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yeah! AUDIENCE MEMBER: Whoo!
(狼吹口哨)
[wolf whistle]
迈克:罗宾·吉文斯。
MIKE: Robin Givens.
(观众窃窃私语)
[audience murmuring]
听着，听着，我们都是婴儿。
Listen, listen, we were babies.
21和22。
21 and 22.
我觉得她很漂亮。
I thought she was so beautiful.
我是说，看看她。
I mean, look at her.
她是个漂亮的女孩，对吧?
She's a beautiful girl, right?
不能得到的。
Unobtainable.
所以我去追她。
So I went after her.
我找到了她。
I tracked her down.
费了点功夫，但我给我们定了个约会。
Took a little work, but I set up a date for us.
你知道，在我的脑海里，就像
You know, in my head, it was like
我在演我自己的浪漫喜剧。
I was in my own version of a fucking rom-com.
(欢快的音乐)
[upbeat music]
罗宾令人印象深刻。
Robin was impressive.
那时电视上很少有年轻的黑人女性。
There were very few young Black women on TV back then.
她是一个榜样，那个it girl。
She was a role model, the it girl.
她是我心目中的童话公主。
She was a fairy-tale princess in my head.
我想成为那种人
I wanted to be the kind of person
罗宾最想爱上的人。
Robin would wanna fall in love with.
歌手:
你问什么都行
SINGERS:
Anything you ask
我会为你做这一切
I'll do it all for you
你照亮了天空
You light the sky everywhere you go
你的目光能使大海平静
Your looks could calm the sea
你让我着迷，这是肯定的
You got me hooked, and that's for sure
这并不奇怪
It's no surprise
-嗨。你一定是迈克尔。
- Hi. You must be Michael.
-是的。
- Yeah.
-我是罗宾。
- I'm Robin.
-我以为你不会跟我约会。
- I didn't think you'd ever go out with me.
我留了很多信息。
I left so many messages.
-我还没听我妈就把它擦掉了
- Oh, that my mother erased before I ever heard them.
但幸运的是，她错过了最后一个。
But, um, luckily, she missed the last one.
-她为什么不想让我们出去?
- Why didn't she want us to go out?
-因为你以打人为生，泰森先生
- Because you hit people for a living, Mr. Tyson.
-迈克尔，这是我妈妈露丝。
- Michael, this is my mother, Ruth.
这是我的公关，斯蒂芬妮。
And this is my publicist, Stephanie.
[轻柔的钢琴曲演奏]
[soft piano music playing]
主持人:这边请。
HOST: Right this way.
迈克:嗯，我不太清楚
MIKE: Um, I don't have a clear understanding
现在正在发生的事情。
One hundred.
of what's going on right now.
罗宾:我妈妈很保护我，
ROBIN: My mother is very protective of me,
她对我们的约会有些担心，
and she had some concerns about us going out,
这就是妥协。
so this is the compromise.
迈克:对。
MIKE: Right.
这可能会让你感到惊讶，但这是绝对不可能的
This might surprise you, but there's no way in hell
我会让我的一个女儿去约会
I'd let one of my daughters go on a date
对我这样的人也一样。
with a guy like me either.
我是说，拜托，是我。
I mean, come on, it's me.
(模糊聊天)
[indistinct chatter]
你知道，这一切都很酷，
Um, you know, this has been cool and all,
但这不是我想象中的那种约会。
but it's not really the kind of date I imagined.
无意冒犯，吉文斯夫人。
No offense, Mrs. Givens.
但我想我要
But I think I'm gonna--
罗宾:哦，等等，等等，请坐。
ROBIN: Oh, wait, wait, please sit down.
嗯…
Um...
我很抱歉。我很紧张。
I'm sorry. I am nervous.
你是迈克·泰森。
You're Mike Tyson.
这很荒谬，我知道，我很抱歉。
This is ridiculous, I know, and I--I'm so sorry.
都是我的错。
It's all my fault.
请不要走?[笑]
Please don't go? [chuckles]
-好吧，我想我们可以在一起。
- Well, I guess we could make this work.
我们他妈成功了。
Oh, we made it fucking work.
(笑声)
[laughter]
这对我来说很富有，你有自己的房间。
That's rich to me, you had your own room.
-它太小了，好吗?
- It was super small, okay?
-我的家人必须分享一切:
- My family had to share everything:
房间，床，我妈和街上的男人。
rooms, beds, my mom with guys off the street.
-甚至你的薯条?
- Even your fries?
- - - - - -[笑]
- [chuckles]
给我留点吧。
Hey, save some of those for me.
-我的天啊。
- Oh, my God.
我好久没吃薯条了。
I haven't had fries in forever.
我对完美有一种奇怪的想法。
I have this whole weird thing with perfection.
因为如果我很完美，他们就伤害不了我。
You know, 'cause if I'm perfect, they can't hurt me.
迈克:嗯。-[笑]
MIKE: Mm. - [chuckles]
我从我妈妈那里学来的。
I learned it from my mom.
我爸爸对她的出轨太严重了，
My dad cheated on her so bad,
所以她只是想确认一下
so she was just trying to make sure
我可以自立了。
I could stand on my own two feet.
-我不太了解我妈。
- I didn't really know my mom.
我没跟她说过话
I didn't have any conversations with her
就像那样，就像我对库斯那样。
like that, like I did with Cus.
我现在有很多事想问她。
There's a lot I wish I could ask her now.
-是啊，我是说
- Mm, yeah, I mean,
我还是不了解我爸爸。
I still don't know my dad.
我总觉得，如果我不是
I always felt like, you know, if I wasn't
够聪明够漂亮还是…
smart enough or pretty enough or...
好到让我爸爸爱我，
good enough for my dad to love me,
为什么会有人爱我?
why would anyone love me?
谁会想到，看看我们，我们也有同样的问题?
Who would think, to look at us, that we got the same problems?
[瓶子碰碰声][两人轻笑]
[bottles clink] [both chuckle]
-不，你太美了。
- No, you are so beautiful.
-我不可怜。
- I'm not pitiful.
-我说的是"美"不是"可怜"
- I said "beautiful," not "pitiful."
-我知道。
- I know.
我只是想听听
I just wanted to hear you say it again.
-我在想，
- You know, I was thinking, um,
也许你可以做我的女朋友。
maybe you could be my girlfriend.
我不想没有你的生活
SINGER:  Didn't wanna live without you
-哦，不。
- Whoa, um, no.
我很抱歉，迈克。我只是——
I'm--I'm sorry, Mike. I just--
听着，过去两周过得很开心，
Look, the last two weeks have been really fun,
但我有很多事要做
but I just got a lot going on.
我是说，机会并不多
I mean, there's not a lot of opportunities
为好莱坞的黑人女演员准备的。
for Black actresses in Hollywood.
我已经22岁了。我时间不多了。
I'm already 22. I don't have a lot of time.
-但我有足够我们俩的钱
- But I--I got enough money for the both of us.
没关系。
It doesn't matter.
-这对我很重要。
- It matters to me.
你已经做到了。你现在是事业的巅峰。
You've already made it. You're at the top of your game.
所有人都盯着你。-是的。
All eyes on you. - Yeah.
罗宾:我不想活在别人的阴影里。
ROBIN: I don't wanna live in someone else's shadow.
我有我自己的梦想。
I got my own dreams.
对不起，迈克。
I'm sorry, Mike.
歌手:
你认为理所当然
SINGER:
You took for granted
-让我们倒带，我告诉你我听到了什么。
- Let's rewind, and I'll tell you what I heard.
(磁带啸声)
[tape squealing]
-黑鬼，你太蠢了，太布朗斯维尔了
- Nigga, you too stupid and too Brownsville
成为我的一切。
to be my everything.
谢谢你的参与。
Thanks for playing.
迈克:但那只会让我更想要她。
MIKE: But that just made me want her more.
我们还在一起玩，
We were still hanging out and stuff,
但这并不代表她就是我的。
but that didn't make her mine.
我希望她是我的。
I wanted her to be mine.
我想如果我给她足够的东西，
You know, I thought if I give her enough stuff,
我可以让她爱上我。
I can make her love me.
不，我对爱情一无所知。
Nah, I didn't know anything about love.
我只知道我在电影里看到的。
I only knew what I saw in the movies.
你知道，这就是我在玩的。
You know, that's what I was playing at.
我曾坠入爱河
I was in love
但以我自己的方式，对吧?
but in my own kind of fucked-up way, right?
(笑声)
[laughter]
(欢快的音乐)
[upbeat music]
-嗨。
- Hi.
-我在找玫瑰。
- I'm looking for some roses.
[门咔哒一声打开]
[door clicks open]
- - - - - -[笑]
- [chuckles]
——(呻吟)
- [moaning]
歌手:
我不能否认
SINGER:
I can't deny
你给我的感觉
The way you make me feel
迈克:我喜欢这个。
MIKE: I like this one.
-不错的选择。
- Excellent choice.
它们是南海珍珠。[笑]
They're Southern Sea pearls. [chuckles]
(喘息)
[gasps]
迈克:也许我和那些女人在一起，因为我从来没有
MIKE: Maybe I was with all those women because I never
我真以为我能搞定罗宾。
really thought I could get Robin.
或者我当时才21岁，很饥渴。
Or maybe I was just 21 and horny.
在和罗宾的求爱过程中，
Through all the courtship with Robin,
我还在战斗。
I was still fighting.
我记得我和破骨者吵了一架。
I remember I had this one fight with Bonecrusher.
他是个特别固执的混蛋。
He was a particularly hardheaded motherfucker.
(普通员工)
[grunts]
(铃响)
[bell dings]
有趣的是，
The funny thing is,
我觉得《破骨者》帮我找到了罗宾。
I think Bonecrusher helped me get Robin.
迈克:嘿。
MIKE: Hey.
-嗨。
- Hey.
我看了这场比赛。你还好吗?
I watched the fight. Are you okay?
迈克:我很好。
MIKE: I'm okay.
虽然很接近。
It was close, though.
我总觉得如果我不赢，人们就会讨厌我。
I always feel like if I don't win, people will hate me.
我真的要挨揍才会有人喜欢我。
Like, I really have to get beat up for somebody to like me.
- - - - - -[笑]
- [chuckles]
我喜欢你，迈克尔。
I like you, Michael.
迈克:如果库斯在这里，我就有人可以说话了。
MIKE: If Cus was here, I'd have somebody to talk to.
吉米是我唯一的亲人了。
Jimmy's all I got now.
-我来了
- Well, I'm here.
-我希望你在这里。
- I wish you were here.
罗宾:迈克尔…(叹息)
ROBIN: Michael...[sighs]
看到你被打，我的心都痛了。
It hurts my heart to see you get hit.
这让我很累。
Like, it takes too much out of me.
它真的让我生病了。
It literally makes me ill.
但是…我只是想保护你。
But...I just wanna protect you.
嘿,迈克尔?
Hey, Michael?
你还想让我做你的女朋友吗?
Do you still want me to be your girl?
——真的吗?
- Really?
你真的想做我的女孩吗?
You really wanna be my girl?
-是的，我知道。
- Yeah, I do.
迈克:是吗?
MIKE: Yeah?
-是啊，我想你。
- Yeah, I--I miss you.
-我要在你改变主意之前把电话挂了。
- I'm gonna hang up the phone before you change your mind.
我有女朋友了。
I got a girlfriend.
-今晚不行，你不行。
- Not tonight, you don't.
【第八天的《她不只是另一个女人》】
[8th Day's "She's Not Just Another Woman"]
歌手:她不只是另一个女人
SINGERS:  She's not just another woman
她不是，不，不
She's not, no, no
她不只是另一个女人
She's not just another woman
她不是，不，不
She's not, no, no
她给了我一个新生的生命
She's given me a newborn birth
我在这苦涩的地球上找到了甜蜜
I found sweetness on this bitter Earth
她知道该说什么
She knows the things to say
帮我摆脱烦恼
To help my troubles away
当她说的话行不通时
And when the words she say won't do
她会试着吻你一两个
She'll try a kiss or two
她是我的，我的，我的
She's mine, mine, mine
她知道如何安慰我
She knows how to console me
她是我的，我的，我的
She's mine, mine, mine
她知道如何控制我
She knows how to control me
我不想让任何人谈论我的宝贝
I don't want nobody talking 'bout my baby
没有人谈论我的宝贝
Nobody talkin' 'bout my baby
罗宾:这是……(笑)
ROBIN: This is...[laughs]
我是说，你知道你没必要这么做，对吧?
I mean, you know you didn't have to do this, right?
-是啊，但这不是那种戒指。
- Yeah, well, it's not that kind of ring.
不是结婚什么的。
Not marriage or anything.
但是，你知道，当你准备好了，告诉我。
But, you know, whenever you're ready, let me know.
我会给你找比这更好更大的。
I'll get you something way better than that, way bigger.
-看看我们。
- Look at us.
我们看起来很有抱负。迈克:是的。
We look aspirational. MIKE: Yeah.
-我是说，我没有榜样
- I mean, I didn't have role models
和我们一样长大的人。
of people who looked like us growing up.
现在我们就是他们。
And now we're them.
这太令人兴奋了。
It's--it's so exciting.
-是的。-你真令人兴奋。
- Yeah. - You're so exciting.
我们太兴奋了。-是的。
We're so exciting. - Yeah.
-想想我们能激励多少人。
- Think of all the people we can inspire.
-是的。
- Yeah.
-说到灵感…
- Speaking of inspiration...
-你给我带来了什么?
- What you got for me?
毫米。
Mm.
(笑)好。
[chuckles] Okay.
好吧。(手铐摇铃)
Okay. [handcuffs rattle]
(有弹性的音乐)
[bouncy music]
-你现在是我的了，冠军。
- You're mine now, champ.
——正确的。
- Right.
(两人都笑)
[both chuckle]
(罗宾唧唧的声音)
[Robin yelps]
迈克:那是我第一次恋爱。
MIKE: It was the first time I was in love.
我们当时只有21岁和22岁。
We were only 21 and 22.
(两个都笑了起来)
[both laugh]
一切发生得太快了。
It was happening so fast.
太快了。
Too fast.
要生孩子了?
Gonna have a baby?
吉米告诉我你怀孕了。
Jimmy told me you're knocked up.
你告诉了我的业务经理，却没告诉我?
You told my business manager, but you didn't tell me?
-我只告诉了我妈
- I only told my mom.
也许她告诉他了?
Maybe she told him?
我不想给你压力。
I didn't wanna pressure you.
可以吗?
Is that okay?
-是的。
- Yeah.
——是吗?-是的。
- Yeah? - Yeah.
澄清一下，罗宾说她怀孕了
To be clear, Robin says she got pregnant
我们结婚后，
after we got married,
但你们都不会花钱去看她的演出。
but y'all aren't paying to see her show.
(笑声)
[laughter]
我做了唯一觉得对的事
I did the only thing that felt right
每次我觉得不对劲的时候。
every time I thought something was wrong.
我更搞砸了。
I fucked it up even more.
-直到死亡将你们分开?
- Till death do you part?
-是的。
- I do.
-你跟我说我们要去看全明星赛。
- You told me we were going to the All-Star Game.
-我觉得这样更浪漫。
- Well, I thought this was more romantic.
-比篮球更浪漫?
- More romantic than basketball?
-你爱我?
- You love me?
(欢快的音乐)
[upbeat music]
-是的。
- I do.
牧师:你可以吻新娘了。
PRIEST: You may kiss the bride.
[欢呼和掌声]
[cheers and applause]
(按快门)-大家放轻松。
[camera shutters clicking] - Relax, everybody.
他马上就出来。
He'll be out in a minute.
天哪。
Sheesh.
三得利干衣店的销售代表在盯着你，
Suntory Dry Man reps have their eyes on you,
所以我们得保证这次旅行干净利落，对吧?
so we gotta keep this trip squeaky-clean, right?
这里是一个不同的市场。
It's a different market here.
没有坏男孩的东西。
No bad-boy stuff.
-我需要预支我的钱包。
- I need an advance on my purse.
我想从日本给罗宾买点好东西。
I wanna get Robin something nice from Japan.
-你在罗宾身上花了很多钱。
- You're spending a lot on Robin.
你需要慢下来。
You need to slow down.
-她是我妻子。我想给她一个惊喜。
- She's my wife. I wanna surprise her.
-好吧，给她爱的礼物。
- All right, give her the gift of love.
(叹息)
[sighs]
好吧，好吧，好吧。
All right, all right, fine.
我看看我能做些什么。
I'll see what I can do.
-为什么不是吉米在管钱?
- Why isn't Jimmy handling the money?
-[深吸一口气]
- [inhales deeply]
牧师:我们祈祷吉米·雅各布斯的灵魂
PRIEST: And we pray that the soul of Jimmy Jacobs
找到它永恒的归宿。
find its eternal resting place.
-这是些真东西。
- So here's some real shit.
吉米，我喜欢的经理，库斯挑选的，
Jimmy, the manager I liked, that Cus had picked,
我病了很多年，他们都瞒着我。
had been sick for years, and they hid it from me.
凯顿让我签了份合同说如果吉米死了，
Cayton got me to sign some contract saying if Jimmy died,
凯顿会自动成为我的经纪人。
Cayton would automatically be my manager.
他们甚至还说要给他们的寡妇
They even put some shit in about giving their widows
我的50%如果他们死了，
50% of me if they died,
就像我是他们可以随意传递的动产
like I was some chattel they could pass around...
就像他们拥有我一样。
Like they own me.
罗宾不喜欢这样，她把他们告得屁滚尿流。
Robin didn't like that, and she sued the fuck out of 'em.
歌手:
太多改变了
SINGER:
So much did change
鲁斯:嗯，谢谢你来见我们。
RUTH: Well, thank you for meeting with us.
既然我女儿现在是迈克尔的代理律师，
Since my daughter is now Michael's power of attorney,
我们想看看他的账目。
we'd like to see his accounts.
-我只是希望我的家庭一切都完美。
- I just want everything to be perfect for my family.
现在需要照顾的不只是我们。
It's not just us we need to look out for now.
迈克:但是罗宾负责我的财务
MIKE: But with Robin doing my finances
吉米突然走了
and with Jimmy suddenly gone,
有人从后门溜进来的。
someone else snuck in the back door.
堂。金:在这场巨大的悲剧中，
DON KING: In this great tragedy,
失去一位朋友和同事，
the loss of a friend and colleague,
这是一个机会。
lays an opportunity.
吉米没走。
Jimmy isn't gone.
他被转化为纯灵了。
He's transferred into pure spirit.
同样的，你和他之间的信任关系
In the--in the same way, your trusting relationship with him
不一定是丢了，只是调走了。
doesn't have to be lost, just transferred.
[笑]
[chuckles]
迈克，你有机会
Mike, you have an opportunity
掌握自己的命运。
to take control of your destiny.
作为一个完全解放的黑人，
As one fully liberated Black man to another,
安慰自己，死亡只是一个过渡，
take solace that death is but a transition,
我是你的重生。
and I am your rebirth.
[笑]
[chuckles]
-他是个迷人的混蛋。
- Oh, he's a charming motherfucker.
啊哈。
Uh-huh.
(欢快的音乐)
[upbeat music]
罗宾:现在，看看巴黎的照片
ROBIN: Now, the pictures from Paris
我们应该在星期五到达。
were supposed to arrive on Friday.
我不明白为什么要耽搁。
I don't understand what the holdup is.
你得给克里斯托夫打个电话。
You need to get on the phone with Christophe.
你知道法国人是什么样的。
You know how these French people are.
你得控制住他们。哦,宝贝。
You have to stay on top of them. Oh, babe.
所以我想要Vulcano丝绸
So I'm thinking Vulcano silk
这个房间，然后也许…
for this room and then maybe a...
迈克:每个人都认为罗宾到处乱跑
MIKE: Everyone has this vision that Robin ran around
所有的装修师都在装修房子。
with all the decorators doing the house.
这是废话。
That's bullshit.
都是我的错。
It was all me.
-我要她没有的。
- I'll have what she's not having.
-为我们完美的新家干杯
- A toast to our perfect new home
还有迈克尔，他将成为最好的父亲，
and to Michael, who is going to be the best father,
谢谢妈妈一直对我们照顾得那么好。
and Mom for always taking such good care of us.
露丝:你们是我的孩子。
RUTH: You're my children.
我的职责是保护你
It's my job to protect you,
尤其是当你甚至不知道你需要它的时候。
especially when you don't even know you need it.
-这是什么意思?
- What's that supposed to mean?
-妈，现在不行。
- Mom, not now.
-你们俩都这么年轻。
- You're both so young.
我只是担心那些人
I'm just concerned that the people who are
本应该照顾你的，却没有。
supposed to be looking out for you aren't.
——嗯…[笑]
- Well... [chuckles]
妈妈想说的是…
What mom is trying to say is...
比尔·凯顿一直在偷我们的钱。
Bill Cayton's been stealing from us.
从你。
From you.
——唐纳德·特朗普提供了他的咨询服务。
- Donald Trump has offered his consulting services.
这才是你可以信任的商人。
Now, that's a businessman you can trust.
-你们就找不到小点的鸡吗?
- You guys couldn't find a smaller chicken?
-是一只鹌鹑。
- It's a quail.
-什么是鹌鹑?
- What's a quail?
唐:(笑)
DON: [laughs]
鹌鹑?该死的!
Quail? Goddamn!
你和鸽子赛跑。你不吃它们!
You race pigeons. You don't eat 'em!
(笑)
[laughs]
那些女人想转化你
Those women are trying to turn you
变成娘娘腔。
into some kind of sissy.
接下来，你就会
Next thing you know, you gonna be
喝着香槟，小指举在空中!
drinking Champale, pinkie in the air!
[笑]
[chuckles]
那个小特是个温柔的白人男孩。
Ooh, that Trump's a tender-handed white boy.
嗯。
Hmm.
他这辈子都没长过老茧。
Never had a callus in his life.
他的钱是他爸爸给的。
Got his money from his daddy.
他们在软化你。
They're softening you up.
你的蛋蛋在她手里。妈妈想要把他们割下来。
Girl's got your balls. Mama's lookin' to cut 'em off.
-那是我老婆
- Man, that's my wife.
——(呻吟)
- [groans]
一个不在乎的人就会闭嘴，
Someone who didn't care would shut the fuck up,
什么也别说。
not say a goddamn word.
但我不能眼睁睁看着冠军变成笨蛋。
But I can't stand by and watch the champ become a chump.
毫米毫米,嗯。
Mm-mm, hmm.
跟着国王，孩子，你会没事的。
Stick with the King, boy, you'll be all right.
[笑]
[chuckles]
迈克:唐说对了一件事。
MIKE: That's one thing Don was right about.
露丝和罗宾抓住了我的蛋蛋。
Ruth and Robin had me by the balls.
所以我和我的蛋蛋开始减少在家的时间。
So me and my balls started spending less time at home.
罗宾:(鼓掌两次)
ROBIN: [claps twice]
现在是凌晨四点。
It's 4:00 a.m.
-我以为你睡着了。
- I thought you were asleep.
-我猜你也有
- Mm, I bet you did.
——嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
-你去哪儿了?
- Where were you?
-我是说我…我是说…
- I mean, I was, um-- I mean...
我和唐在一起。
I was with Don.
是的。-真的吗?
Yeah. - Oh, really?
那是唐的颜色吗?
Is that Don's color?
-好吧，我不用告诉你
- Okay, I don't have to tell you
我去过哪里，和谁在一起，好吗?
where I've been or who I've been with, okay?
-[嘲笑]天啊，迈克，
- [scoffs] Jesus, Mike,
这跟我爸干的一模一样!
this is the same shit my dad did, the same shit!
我警告过你。
I warned you.
-警告我?-是的。
- Warned me? - Yeah.
-听着，你和你妈妈不能变成冠军
- Listen, you and your mother can't turn the champ
变成笨蛋，好吗?
into a chump, all right?
-你在说什么?
- What are you talking about?
-你根本不在乎我。
- You don't care about me.
你只关心花我的钱。
All you care about is spending my money.
-我是想保护你
- I'm trying to protect you
从偷你钱的人那里。
from people who are stealing your money.
-这样你就可以花了。
- So you can spend it.
罗宾:我要把钱花在你身上。
ROBIN: I'm spending it on you.
你不明白我们需要一切都完美无缺
You don't understand that we need everything to be perfect
因为每个人都在看。
because everyone is watching.
你会怎么做?
And what do you do?
你出轨的程度比我爸还严重。
You go out and you're cheating worse than my dad.
-我真希望你没怀孕
- You know, I wish you weren't pregnant
这样我就不用和你结婚了
so I wouldn't have had to get married to you.
-你的愿望实现了，迈克尔
- Well, you got your wish, Michael.
-那时她告诉我她把孩子弄丢了。
- That's when she told me she lost the baby.
罗宾说她在医院把孩子弄丢了
Robin said she lost the baby in the hospital
我和她在一起
and I was with her.
我不知道。
I don't know.
她写了她的书，我写了我的。
She wrote her book, and I wrote mine.
我只知道，我想要那种梦幻般的生活
What I do know is, I wanted that fantasy life
为了罗宾，我什么都愿意给她。
for Robin so bad, I would've given her anything.
嗯，几乎任何事情。
Well, almost anything.
(门铃响了)
[doorbell rings]
卡米尔:迈克尔!
CAMILLE: Michael!
迈克:见到你真高兴!
[squeals] MIKE: It's so good to see you!
- - - - - -[笑]
- [chuckles]
哦!
Oh!
你看起来不错，我的帅哥。
Oh, you look good, my handsome boy.
-谢谢。
- Thank you.
我想让你见见我美丽的，
I want you to meet my beautiful,
惊人的罗宾…和露丝。
stunning Robin... and Ruth.
-你本人更可爱。
- And you are so much more lovely in person.
(咯咯地笑)罗宾:哦，天哪。
[giggles] ROBIN: Oh, my.
卡米尔:我特意为你做了肉汁。
CAMILLE: I made extra gravy just for you.
-谢谢，卡米尔。
- Thanks, Camille.
露丝:[深吸一口气]
RUTH: [inhales deeply]
你的家真漂亮，卡米尔。
Uh, you have such a beautiful home, Camille.
那个放着迈克尔所有奖项和奖章的房间，
That room with all of Michael's awards and, uh, medals,
它就像一个神殿。
it's like a shrine.
我想威少是真的爱——迈克:因为。
I guess Russ really did love-- MIKE: Cus.
他的名字叫库斯。
His name is Cus.
露丝:对。
RUTH: Right.
我想库斯真的很爱迈克尔。
I guess Cus really loved Michael.
卡米尔:嗯，每个人都喜欢迈克尔，
CAMILLE: Well, everyone loves Michael,
特别是客户。
especially Cus.
他为迈克尔在拳击场上的出色表现感到骄傲。
He was so proud of how great Michael was in the ring.
即使在床上，他也会谈论他。
Even in bed, he talks about him.
[笑]
[chuckles]
“我最伟大的创造，”他说。
"My greatest creation," he'd say.
(餐具无比的)
[cutlery clinking]
-太有意思了。
- Just so interesting.
我想，鉴于迈克尔是上帝最伟大的创造，
I guess, given that Michael is Cus' greatest creation,
让他为你的房子买单可以吗?
it's okay for him to be paying for your house?
-我——迈克:罗宾。
- I-- MIKE: Robin.
罗宾:不，我——我很抱歉。
ROBIN: No, I'm--I'm so sorry.
我只是想知道为什么…
I'm just wondering why it is that...
我丈夫在外面
my husband is out there
在拳击场上摧毁他的身体
destroying his body in the ring
同时，用我们的钱
and, meanwhile, using our money
为这里的一切买单。
to pay for everything in here.
——罗宾。ROBIN:[笑]
- Robin. ROBIN: [chuckles]
这似乎是永无止境的
And it seems to just be never-end--
[手碰桌子]
[hand bangs on table]
(板咔嗒咔嗒声)
[plate rattling]
(手砰砰声)
[hand thuds]
迈克:你怎么了?
MIKE: What's the matter with you?
-你得看看里面发生了什么。
- You need to see what's going on in there.
迈克:那边那位女士是我的——罗宾:你的什么?
MIKE: That lady in there's my-- ROBIN: Your what?
她不是你的家人。
She's not your family.
因为他利用了你。——没有。
Cus used you. - No.
罗宾:她在利用你。——没有。
ROBIN: She's using you. - No.
-他们伤害了你，而你，你是
- They damaged you, and you're--you're, what,
你付钱给他们?
you're paying them for it?
你太渴望有人爱你了
You're so desperate for someone to love you
你会重写故事，只为让你感受到爱。
that you'll rewrite the story just so you feel love.
那我的故事呢?
But--but what about my story?
我爱你，你却因此恨我。
I love you, and you hate me for it.
你身边没有人，所以你让克劳斯转化了你
You didn't have anyone, so you let Cus turn you
变成了他的野兽，现在你却在这里
into his brute, and now you're out here
为这个白人老太太的房子买单，
paying for this old white lady's house,
像雇工一样给她修剪草坪。
mowing her lawn like the hired help.
为了什么?
And for what?
因为她给你额外的肉汁还冲你笑?
Because she gives you extra gravy and smiles at you?
别那么天真。
Don't be so naive.
-管好你的嘴，贱人
- You watch your mouth, bitch.
-哦，真有趣。
- Oh, that's funny.
一分钟前，你还叫我宝贝。
Just a minute ago, you were calling me baby.
-我说真的，罗宾我——
- I mean it, Robin. I--
(咆哮)
[growls]
(拳头重击声)
[fist thuds]
我不知道怎么拼才会输，只会赢。
I don't know how to fight to lose, only to win.
我也不知道如何去爱赢。
I don't know how to love to win either.
[比尔·威瑟斯的《美好的一天》]
[Bill Withers' "Lovely Day"]
医生:锂应该有助于稳定
DOCTOR: The lithium should help stabilize
你的情绪和行为。
your moods and behavior.
-药物通常不会让我更稳定。
- Pills don't usually make me more stable.
医生:躁狂抑郁症是一场终生的战斗，迈克。
DOCTOR: Manic depression is a lifelong battle, Mike.
你很幸运有这么好的支持系统。
You're lucky to have such a great support system.
迈克:罗宾说她很担心我，
MIKE: Robin said she was worried about me,
我吓到她了
that I was scaring her,
她只希望我过得好。
that she only wanted the best for me.
她没有意识到的是……
What she didn't realize was...
当我喝酒或做饭的时候
When I drink or do coke, I'm gonna fight you.
当我抽大麻的时候，我会把我所有的钱给你。
When I smoke weed, I'm gonna give you all my money.
这不是躁狂抑郁症。那是吸毒的我。
That's not manic depression. That's me on drugs.
比尔·威瑟斯:“还有毫无征兆的爱。
BILL WITHERS:  And something without warning, love
沉重地压在我的心头
Bears heavy on my mind
-该吃药了，宝贝。
- It's time for your medicine, baby.
比尔:
然后我看着你
BILL:
Then I look at you
全世界对我来说都很好
And the world's all right with me
就看你一眼
Just one look at you
(铃响)
[bell dings]
-他吃什么药?
- What is he on?
-他说是锂。——锂。
- He says it's lithium. - Lithium.
他是个拳击手，不是家庭主妇。他不会打架。
He a boxer, not a housewife. He can't fight.
-他移动得很好。
- He's moving all right.
-你觉得他像个重量级人物吗?
- He look like a heavyweight to you?
罗宾:我给你做点别的，好吗，宝贝?
ROBIN: I'm gonna make you something else, okay, baby?
歌手:
可爱的一天，可爱的一天
SINGER:
Lovely day, lovely day
可爱的一天，可爱的一天
可爱的一天，可爱的一天，可爱的一天
Lovely day, lovely day, lovely day
露丝:你不能一直假装
RUTH: You cannot keep pretending
你能搞定他的。
you can fix his shit.
相信我。
Trust me.
-他是我丈夫。
- He is my husband.
-是啊，我听到你们在喊
- Yeah, and I hear y'all yelling,
我知道他是干什么的
and I know what he does.
你知道我也经历过这种事。
You know I've been through this shit.
-别说了。
- Stop it.
我要解决这个问题。
I'm going to fix this.
比尔:
似乎无法面对
BILL:
Seems impossible to face
-至少我觉得他们是这么说的。
- At least, that's what I thought they said.
我当时醉得不知道。
I was too fucked up to know.
说到搞砸了…
Oh, speaking of fucked up...
[汽车喇叭声]
[car horn blaring]
比尔:世界对我来说很好
BILL:  And the world's all right with me
就看你一眼
Just one look at you
我知道它会是
And I know it's gonna be
迈克:他们称之为反常行为。
MIKE: They called it erratic behavior.
比尔:
可爱的一天
BILL:
A lovely day
迈克:但那是个意外。
MIKE: But it was an accident.
(咳嗽)
[coughs]
罗宾说她以为是自杀未遂。
Robin said she thought it was a suicide attempt.
接下来你知道，
The next thing you know,
报纸也在说同样的话。
papers are saying the same thing.
比尔:
可爱的一天
BILL:
A lovely day
迈克:就在俄罗斯事件之后，
MIKE: Right after that was the Russia incident,
你知道，这完全是夸大其词。
which, you know, was totally overblown.
罗宾和露丝是这么说的，
This is what Robin and Ruth said happened,
但我嗑了锂，可卡因，
but hey, I was on lithium, coke,
当时还有大麻，所以谁他妈知道?
and weed at the time, so who the fuck knows?
但我必须控制损失，
But I had to do damage control,
所以我和芭芭拉·沃尔特斯谈过了
so I talked to Barbara Walters
看起来像个该死的风筝。
looking high as a motherfucking kite.
我们都知道结果如何。
And we all know how that turned out.
芭芭拉:我们读过的一些东西……
BARBARA: Some of the things we've read...
他打了你
that he's hit you,
他在俄罗斯追着你和你妈妈跑
that he's chased you and your mother around in--in Russia,
迈克的脾气反复无常……
that Mike has a very volatile temper...
真的吗?
True?
-极不稳定。
- Extremely volatile.
这是可怕的。
It's scary.
芭芭拉:发生了什么?
BARBARA: What happens?
他打你了吗?
Does he hit you?
-他抖了抖。
- He shakes.
他把。
He pushes.
他的波动。
He swings.
很长一段时间，我以为我能应付得了。
For a long time, I thought I could handle it.
我最近才开始害怕。
I've only recently become afraid.
迈克尔患有躁狂抑郁症。
Michael is a manic-depressive.
他是。这是事实。
He is. That's a fact.
他有这个病很久了。
He's had it for a long time.
没有得到治疗，情况变得更糟了。
It went untreated, and it got worse.
芭芭拉:你认为为什么以前没有人看到它?
BARBARA: Why do you think no one saw it before?
因为达马托没有看到。比尔·凯顿没有看到。
Cus D'Amato didn't see it. Bill Cayton didn't see it.
-[猛呼一口气]
- [exhales sharply]
我无法想象有人能忍受迈克·泰森，
I can't imagine that anyone could live with Mike Tyson,
我知道的那个
the one that I know,
却不知道有什么问题。
and not see that there's a problem.
打老师,
Hitting teachers,
打女孩，把她们拉进浴室。
hitting girls and pulling them into the bathroom.
芭芭拉:那为什么不治疗呢?
BARBARA: So why wasn't it treated?
-因为他在拳击场上表现出色。
- Because he did well in the ring.
非常好。
Exceptionally well.
迈克:我希望有人告诉我
MIKE: I wish someone told me
即使是童话也需要婚前协议。
that even fairy tales need a prenup.
罗宾从未要求过赡养费，
Robin never actually asked for alimony,
但她提出了索赔1.25亿美元的诽谤诉讼。
but she did file a $125 million libel suit.
我的浪漫喜剧就完了。
And poof goes my rom-com.
我的婚姻完蛋了。
Poof goes my marriage.
也许我们从一开始就注定要失败。
Probably we were doomed from the start.
当你恨自己的时候，你就无法爱别人。
When you hate yourself, you can't love someone else.
这是一种很空虚的感觉，当唯一的东西
It's a very empty feeling when the only thing
你可以依靠他的战斗，
you can rely on is fighting,
但那就是我。
but that's who I was.
这就是他们想要的人。
That's who they still wanted.
那就是你们一直想要的人。
That's who you all still wanted.
(音乐的)
[somber music]
脱口秀主持人:我，呃，我的一天开始得很奇怪。
TALK SHOW HOST: My, uh-- my day started off weird.
我今天买了一张彩票，
I bought a lottery ticket today,
上面写着:“恭喜你，
and it said, "Congratulations,
你可能已经是罗宾·吉文斯的下一任丈夫了。”
you may already be Robin Givens' next husband."
(笑声)
[laughter]
记者:一个野心勃勃的拜金女
REPORTER: An ambitious gold digger
谁要泰森一半的收入
who's demanding half of what Tyson made
在他们短暂的八个月婚姻中，
during their short, eight-month marriage,
包括泰森获得的2100万美元
including the $21 million Tyson earned
在91秒的淘汰赛中
at his remarkable 91-second knockout fight
迈克尔·斯宾克斯。
with Michael Spinks.
记者:世界重量级冠军之间的较量越来越激烈了
REPORTER: Getting ugly between the world heavyweight champion
据知情人士透露，她还是情景喜剧演员
and the sitcom actress, as sources are claiming
罗宾·吉文斯和她的母亲露丝
Robin Givens and her mother, Ruth,
“总是在徘徊吗?
were "always on the prowl
为罗宾找个黑人名人。”
for a big Black celebrity for Robin."
《新闻之夜》民调显示，即将成为前夫人的希拉里。泰森
NewsNight polls ranked the soon-to-be ex-Mrs. Tyson
明确的持有人
the unequivocal holder
世界上最讨厌的女人的头衔。
of the Most Hated Woman in the World title.
(音乐的)
[somber music]
迈克:我的婚姻结束了。
MIKE: My marriage was over.
也许我不讨人喜欢，就像我妈妈说的。
Maybe I was unlovable, like my mom said.
也许我永远不可能和任何人单独相处。
Maybe I could never have that one-on-one with anybody.
记者:迈克·泰森今天得到了支持
REPORTER: Mike Tyson got support today
从说话时语速很快…
from fast-talking...
迈克:我只是厌倦了那种难受的感觉。
MIKE: I was just so tired of feeling bad.
但后来我意识到……
But then I realized...
他们仍然爱我。
They still love me.
现在我真的要找点乐子了。
Now I'm really gonna have some fun.
[欢快的嘻哈音乐]
[upbeat hip-hop music]
歌手:钱使世界转动
SINGER:  Money make the world go round
我要把我的钱拿起来，所以你最好下来
I gotta get my funds up, so you better get down
我是来找乐子的，跟我一起玩吧
I came for the guap, fuck around with me
我会让我们都过上奢华的生活
I'll have us all living in the lap of luxury
因为金钱让世界转动
'Cause money make the world go round
歌手:
是的，是的
SINGER:
Yeah, yeah
歌手:钱使世界转动
SINGER:  Money make the world go round
歌手:
是的，是的
SINGER:
Yeah, yeah
歌手:钱使世界转动
SINGER:  Money make the world go round
来和我一起喝一杯，或者躺在床上
Come get some with me or get laid the fuck down
让我告诉你我来自哪里
Let me show you where I'm from
你得系好鞋带
Gotta keep your shoes laced up
如果你要跑的话歌手:呜呜，呜呜
In case you gotta run  SINGER:  Whoop, whoop
歌手:
从街上的男孩那里
SINGER:
From the boys on the block
如果不是男孩，那就是帮派的标志
And if it ain't the boys, it's the gang signs
在它爆掉之前就扔了
Thrown before it pops
不要被夹在交火的中间
Don't get caught up in the middle of the crossfire
子弹是没有名字的，当你走过它们
Bullets ain't got no names when you walk by 'em
不要看，当我们走过的时候就完成了
Don't look, be done when we come through
快跑吧，因为你知道枪的作用
Just run, 'cause you know what the gun do
每个人都想远离街头
E'rybody wanna be from the streets
直到他们看到他们的男人坐在六英尺深的地方
Until they see their man sitting six feet deep
棺材上有鲜花
With the flowers on the casket
他们的妈妈站在场边
And their mom on the sideline
哭着说:“亲爱的上帝，不，不，为什么是我的?”
Crying like, "Dear Lord, no, no, why mine?"
因为街上没有孩子是安全的
'Cause no child in the streets here safe
不惜一切代价去做
By any means necessary, do what it takes